<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mata on Álvaro A. Gutiérrez Vargas</title>
    <link>/tags/mata/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mata on Álvaro A. Gutiérrez Vargas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/mata/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to write your own command to fit a likelihood using a Mata evaluator with ml command on Stata</title>
      <link>/2020/07/04/how-to-write-your-own-command-to-fit-a-likelihood-using-a-mata-evaluator-with-ml-command-on-stata/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/04/how-to-write-your-own-command-to-fit-a-likelihood-using-a-mata-evaluator-with-ml-command-on-stata/</guid>
      <description>If you are reading this you should be quite desperate to get an answer about how to deal with the impossible [holy] trinity of put together a (1) d-family Mata evaluator, within an (2) ado file (a.k.a your own new command) that performs a maximum likelihood estimation using (3) -ml- invoking your Mata evaluator. Let me say that you are probably (?) in the write place.
Indeed, this post is an improved version of a later post where I fitted a conditional logit using -ml- with Mata-based likelihood function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fitting Conditional Logit using d0 Mata-based evaluator using maximum likelihood -ml- on Stata</title>
      <link>/2020/05/01/fitting-conditional-logit-using-d0-mata-based-evaluator-using-maximum-likelihood-ml-on-stata/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/05/01/fitting-conditional-logit-using-d0-mata-based-evaluator-using-maximum-likelihood-ml-on-stata/</guid>
      <description>This post is higly based on the excellent book Maximum likelihood estimation with Stata. Stata press Gould, W., Pitblado, J., &amp;amp; Sribney, W. (2006) and by any means tries to be a replacement for such an amazing reference. However, within the chapter 6 devoted to d-family -ml- evaluators, somehow something, in my humble opinion, very important was missing. The missing part was the discussion of Discrete Choice Models as a particular family of models specially suitable for such family of evaluators where ikelihood function does not meet the linearform restrictions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>