<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stata on Álvaro A. Gutiérrez Vargas</title>
    <link>/tags/stata/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stata on Álvaro A. Gutiérrez Vargas</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/stata/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Monte Carlo Simulation of your own Stata command</title>
      <link>/2020/07/05/monter-carlo-simulation-of-your-own-stata-command/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/05/monter-carlo-simulation-of-your-own-stata-command/</guid>
      <description>This the final step of a series of earlier post where I dealed with the combination of a Mata evaluators within ado files that uses ml to fit Maximum Likelihood Estimations. Here a single dofile is used but it relies in what we have done in my previous post when we built up MyClogit command.
The only file needed is the following, and it can be downloaded by clicking on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Write your own command to fit a likelihood using a Mata-evaluator with ml command on Stata</title>
      <link>/2020/07/04/how-to-write-your-own-command-to-fit-a-likelihood-using-a-mata-evaluator-with-ml-command-on-stata/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/04/how-to-write-your-own-command-to-fit-a-likelihood-using-a-mata-evaluator-with-ml-command-on-stata/</guid>
      <description>If you are reading this you should be quite desperate to get an answer about how to deal with the impossible [holy] trinity of put together a (1) d-family Mata evaluator, within an (2) ado file (a.k.a your own new command) that performs a maximum likelihood estimation using (3) -ml- invoking your Mata evaluator. Let me say that you are probably (?) in the write place.
Indeed, this post is an improved version of a later post where I fitted a conditional logit using -ml- with Mata-based likelihood function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fitting Conditional Logit using d0 Mata-based evaluator using maximum likelihood -ml- on Stata</title>
      <link>/2020/07/03/fitting-conditional-logit-using-d0-mata-based-evaluator-using-maximum-likelihood-ml-on-stata/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/07/03/fitting-conditional-logit-using-d0-mata-based-evaluator-using-maximum-likelihood-ml-on-stata/</guid>
      <description>This post is higly based on the excellent book Maximum likelihood estimation with Stata. Stata press Gould, W., Pitblado, J., &amp;amp; Sribney, W. (2006) and by any means tries to be a replacement for such an amazing reference. However, within the chapter 6 devoted to d-family -ml- evaluators, somehow something, in my humble opinion, very important was missing. The missing part was the discussion of Discrete Choice Models as a particular family of models specially suitable for such family of evaluators where ikelihood function does not meet the linearform restrictions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Are my labels there? Searching among label variables values on Stata</title>
      <link>/2020/06/27/are-my-labels-there-searching-among-label-values-on-stata/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/2020/06/27/are-my-labels-there-searching-among-label-values-on-stata/</guid>
      <description>The problem This brief post answer the question my orignal google search How to check if a value is contained into a label variable on stata?
Imagine we have a problem where we need to check if a string is contained into the labels of another variable. Let’s start with a minimal example using sysuse auto and the variable foreing which is the only one with labels already in place.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[Oto-2019]: StataLaTeX Combo</title>
      <link>/teaching/statalatexcombo/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/statalatexcombo/</guid>
      <description>Este es un compedio del material impartido en el Taller Stata &amp;amp; LaTeX a los alumnos del curso de Econometría Financiera del Master de Finanzas de la Universidad de Chile.
S01: Introduccion a LaTeX Enunciado
 S02: Estadística Descriptiva Enunciado Solución Data
 S03: Manejo de Bases de Datos Enunciado Solución Data
 S04: Trabajo con Multi-bases de Datos Enunciado Solución Data
 S05: Loops &amp;amp; Macros &amp;amp; Automatización Season 1 Enunciado Solución Data</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>